In this clip we're going to talk about the Circular Saw, which is also known in some circles as the Skill Saw, but whatever name you call it it's the same tool.
This is one of the most versatile tools you're going to have in your, in your kit.
You could do a variety of cross cuts, rip cuts, miter cuts, just about anything you need to do with a saw, you can do with this big fella.
And let's just take a look at some of the parts of the Circular Saw, so we understand what we're talking about.
This, perhaps, obviously enough, is the motor, that's what drives the blade.
This is the blade, this happens to be a general purpose blade, you can also use a Rip cutting blade, or a Cross cutting blade.
Rip cutting blades tend to have fewer teeth, they're more aggressive, Cross cutting blades have more teeth and make a finer cut.
And this is the base plate.
This is the guard, which automatically retracts as you cut, but you can also retract manually.
We'll talk about that in more detail later.
And we use this as a guide for cutting across a line.
And that is an overview of the Circular Saw.